Don't underestimate him.
The Amateur is a thriller, action film directed by James Hawes.
After his life is turned upside down when his wife is killed in a London terrorist attack, a brilliant but
introverted CIA decoder takes matters into his own hands when his supervisors refuse to take action.
Heller, played by Rami Malek.
Director Moore, played by Holt McCallany.
Caleb, played by Danny Sapani.
Sarah, played by Rachel Brosnahan.
Schiller, played by Michael Stuhlbarg.
Henderson, played by Laurence Fishburne.
The Amateur is a 2025 American action thriller film directed by
James Hawes and written by Ken Nolan and Gary Spinelli.
It is based on the 1981 novel by Robert Littell, which was
previously adapted into a 1981 Canadian film.
It stars Rami Malek (who also produced), Rachel Brosnahan, Caitríona Balfe, Michael
Stuhlbarg, Holt McCallany, Julianne Nicholson, and Laurence Fishburne.
The film was released in the United States by 20th
Century Studios on April 11, 2025.
It received mixed reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of central intelligence agency (cia),
based on novel or book, escape, blackmail, revenge.
The tone is intense.